# **Roger Cantor** | Solutions Architect

Location: Hertfordshire Telephone: 07932 499 349 Email: roger.cantor@live.com

# **Professional Summary**

I am a highly motivated and passionate Solutions Architect with a broad knowledge of Microsoft Core Infrastructure and Cloud technologies. I have been working in the IT industry for over 20 years and have successfully designed and implemented a large number of technical and managed service business solutions within a variety of industries including large multi-site UK and multinational organisations, government authorities as well as smaller SME business.

I am comfortable working both on my own and as part of a wider projects team and I possess a strong business understanding and excellent technical skills. I am able to provide technical support throughout all stages of a consultative engagement including pre-sales, design, implementation, transition and support; and I can confidently discuss technical solutions at all levels, with colleagues and to both end users and management at all levels.

# **Recent Projects**

- Active Directory/Core Infrastructure
  - o Designed and implemented Active Directory Health Check and Remediation services to multiple customers
  - Redesigned various Active Directory Domain structures for simplified management of delegated security and Group Policy deployment
  - Designed the deployment of Hyper-V infrastructure services to 35 sites during a business acquisition. This included extending the Active Directory/DHCP infrastructure and deployment of local Application services for EPOS.
- Desktop Transformation
  - Designed and implemented a 2500 user migration from Windows 7 to Windows 10 including the upgrade and reconfiguration of supporting Microsoft App-V, Citrix XenApp and Ivanti Workspace Manager technologies.
- Hybrid Cloud Infrastructure
  - Setup various Azure Tenancies for hosting of virtual machines and Azure Active Directory
  - o Designed a centralised and branch office shared storage service utilising Azure Files and Azure FileSync
  - o Deployed Azure ExpressRoute and GlobalReach to enable datacentre connectivity between EMEA and APAC regions
  - Defined the migration strategy for multiple customers server infrastructure to Private Cloud services

### **Principal Skills**

Public and Private Cloud
Azure – Compute, Networking and Storage Fundamentals

Office 365 – Exchange Online / Skype Online / OneDrive for Business

**Datacentre** – Networking and Storage Fundamentals

**Virtualisation** – Hyper-V 2008 R2 – 2016 / VMware 2.5 – 6.1

Server
OS – Windows NT – Windows Server 2016

Active Directory - Domain Services 2003-2016 / Group Policy / Federation Services

File and Print - Distributed File System / Branch Office

Communication – Exchange 2003 – 2008 R2 / Skype for Business

• Workstation OS – Windows 3.1 – Windows 10

Office Suite - Office 4 - 2016 / Office 365 Pro Plus

**Client Application** – MSI/EXE Packaging / App-V Virtualisation **Management** – SCCM 2012 – 2016 / WSUS / AppSense

Virtualisation – Remote Desktop Services 2008 R2 – 2016 / Quest vWorkspace 5.1 – 7.6

• Miscellaneous Security – Sophos Endpoint Protection, SafeGuard Encryption and Mobile Control

Scripting – PowerShell, VBScript, WMI, AutoIT, Command Line

Web Design – HTML, HTA, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

### **Employment History**

# INAK

#### **Head of Pre-sales and Architecture**

January 2018 - Present

In conjunction with providing ongoing Solution Architecture, I took responsibility for the Professional Services team of in-house consultants and external contractors.

- Provided the technical ownership and design of multiple full Managed Service outsource engagements that included hosting, migration and support services
- Took a lead role in the Technical Steering Group to design the Technical Product and Service portfolio of the business
- Provided full ownership and sign-off of all project designs and documentation
- Managed on boarding contractor resources to support project delivery demands
- Implemented a Project Resource Booking and Time Recording system to provide the business with monthly Professional Service financial and performance reports
- Working with the Managed Services lead, designed the service products for the in-house multi-tenanted server hosting, backup and monitoring services



#### **Solutions Architect**

January 2014 - June 2014

Provided support to the Sales team for Technical Pre-Sales of new opportunities and leads as well as producing detailed design proposals of the required solutions. Some of the projects I carried out included:

- Designed and delivered multiple infrastructure health check and remediation projects including Active Directory, SCCM and Exchange.
- Designed a Novell to Microsoft migration project for Directory Services, Email and File & Print services
- Carried out multiple Mobile Device Management Business Discovery and Recommendation engagements
- Designed and implemented Windows Server 2003 upgrade projects for both server OS and Active Directory



#### **Technical Architect**

April 2011 – December 2012

As Technical Architect, I designed all technical solutions required by the customer and engaged with product specialists to assist in designing the solution. I was involved with the preliminary customer scoping discussions, solution design, project delivery and ensuring the technology is accepted into support. My work has included:

- Designed and implemented a 4000 user VDI solution based on Hyper-V
- Designed a Microsoft File and Print infrastructure for migration from Novell NetWare
- Designed and implemented a large multi-site DFS Replication infrastructure to provide off-site backup
- Designed a number of bespoke multi-environment application Systems
- Desktop Management Infrastructure build and migration to Novell ZENworks 11
- Designed a 600 user offline VDI solution for remote working using Citrix XenClient
- Designed the infrastructure for Forefront Endpoint Security to 6000 clients
- Designed the solution to provide password self-service using Forefront Identity Manager



### **Senior Support Engineer**

March 2002 - March 2004

Part of an eight man senior support team providing Server and 3rd Line desktop support for Hertfordshire County Council. Also part of a three man team providing 1st and 2nd Line telephone support to all of the elected County Councillors.

- Senior product lead for LANDesk at HCC and other Regional Sites, providing assistance to onsite 2nd and 3rd Line Support teams with day to day LANDesk issues
- Involved in the design, upgrade and implementation for several organisations from LANDesk 6.62 to LANDesk 8.1
- Packaging and deployment of all small and complex client applications
- Resolution of 3rd Line desktop and Windows Server calls ensuring to meet the contractual SLA's



#### **2nd Line Support Engineer**

March 1998 - April 1999

Worked in a six man 2nd Line Support team providing software and hardware fault resolution to users at Hertfordshire County Council.

# IINAK

#### **Senior Solutions Architect**

July 2014 - December 2017

Lead Solutions Architect attending customer meetings to provide initial scoping, discovery and pre-sales support alongside Sales and SME Consultants. Some of the activities I carried out included:

- Infrastructure consolidation of Active Directory, SCCM and Citrix Environments
- Designed and managed the migration for multiple customers from an onpremises infrastructure to both Office 365, Azure and AWS
- Design, Implementation and Transition to Windows 10 and supporting technologies for multiple customers
- Assisted in defining and growing the technical portfolio of the business
- Provided overall control of the documentation templates and review processes
- Designed and implemented managed Security Vulnerability Management and Patching Services for multiple customers



#### **Solutions Architect**

January 2013 - December 2013

I was responsible for working alongside the Sales team to provide technical assistance during initial customer meetings. After which, I would design and plan the technical requirements of the project, so that a smooth handover to the technical consultant can be achieved for delivery. My recent projects have included:

- Designed and Implemented Hyper-V Clustered environments for Server Virtualisation
- Designed and Implemented Active Directory Migrations and Upgrades
- Designed SCCM 2012 deployments for Office and Mobile based Desktop Management
- Reviewed and consolidated all satellite services into the datacentre including DHCP and File Services



#### **Senior Projects Engineer**

March 2004 - March 2011

Part of four man senior projects team carrying out all high level projects required by the customer. Projects included:

- Designed and automated the migration from Lotus Notes to Microsoft Outlook
- Designed and automated a 6500 user migration from eDirectory into Active Directory
- Implemented a 1000 user Desktop Virtualisation solution with Quest vWorkspace
- Designed and implemented a technology refresh migration to 6500 users including a clustered NetWare File and Print service, ZENworks Desktop Management and Windows XP
- Automated a Workstation Imaging process with a Hardware Independent Image
- Packaged over 300 applications for the automated delivery by the Support team
- Planned and implemented the migration from Windows NT domain to Server 2003 Active Directory
- Led a small team to design and implement a full Desktop Management solution at other Serco contracts



#### **Projects Engineer**

April 1999 – February 2002

Working in a six-man team to deliver project work for Hertfordshire County Council.

- Produced costed Project Proposals from an Outline Project Brief ensuring to meet the Project Sponsor's needs and requirements.
- Involved in the initial implementation of a rolling 3-year Leased PC Programme
- Building and managing PC Images and the rollout of PC's to small and large Office
- Building of Windows NT and 2000 Servers
- Liaising with 3rd Party companies to configure Application Servers as required for the business
- Setting up of new Offices with File and Print Services, Desktop and Laptop PC's, Email Systems and Comms Equipment, whilst managing an issues register and resolving any problems encountered



2nd Line PC Support

March 1997 - March 1998

I worked in a four man PC Support Team supporting users in both the head office and around the UK in branch offices.

# **Training and Education**

2016	Sophos Certified Engineer	Passed
2013	MCITP: Virtualization Administrator on Windows Server 2008 R2	Certified
2013	Windows Server 2008 R2, Desktop Virtualisation	Passed
2013	Windows Server 2008 R2, Server Virtualization	Passed
2013	Windows Server 2008 R2, Virtualization Administrator	Passed
2013	Microsoft System Center Operations Manager 2007, Configuring	Passed
2010	Active Directory Design and Implementation	
2010	SCCM 2007	
2009	ZCM 10 Support and Administration	
2009	NetApp Support	
2009	CommVault Support	
2008	VMware 3.5	
2006	ZENworks 6.5 Advanced Administration	
2004	LANDesk 8	Certified
2001	Windows 2000 Design and Implementation	
2000	Novell 4.11 Administration	Certified
1999	NT4 Administration	
1998	Data Communications and Networking	Level 2
1997	PC Support	Level 1
1997	Windows 95 Support	
1997	Computers and Computing	Level 1
1997	Basic Microsoft Excel	
1995	Ware Business College	
	Sage Accounting	Distinction
1989–1995	Ward Freman School, Buntingford	
	A-Level Mathematics	

# **Hobbies and Interests**

I actively play Football, Squash and Snooker; regularly go cycling and to the cinema; and enjoy listening to live music and socialising with friends. I also collect and restore classic Video Arcade Machines, along with hosting Retro Videogame events for the public.

## References

Personal and Employee references are available on request.

8 GCSEs (Grades A-C)